Bloom Southwest Jewish Archives photograph collection, 1850-1995
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Bloom Southwest Jewish Archives photograph collection, 1850-1995
SJA 006
Bloom Southwest Jewish Archives
3.5 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Organization
This collection is organized into five series
Series 1: Arizona
Series 2: New Mexico
Series 3: Texas
Series 4: California
Series 5: Miscellaneous
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains photographs and negatives, copyprints, photocopies, slides, and contact prints which depict wide-ranging types of subject matter regarding Jewish individuals and institutions. The bulk of the photographs were made in the South west United States, principally Arizona, California, Texas, and New Mexico. These photographs are especially revealing of the role of Jews in the establishment of commercial, religious, and other communal institutions in the American West during the seco nd half of the nineteenth century and the early decades of the twentieth century. Also present are more contemporary depictions of Jewish individuals and groups which have been prominent in this geographic region.
The collection also contains a few photographs from Michigan, Colorado, Israel, Europe, Latin America, and other locations.
Items are arranged by the state in which the depicted object was located, then alphabetically within the state according to the name of the relevant individual, institution, or the subject matter of the photograph.
The states listed are Arizona, California, New Mexico, and Texas. A final category includes photographs from all other locations.
Where a negative or slides are present, that has been indicated in CAPS in the finding aid
Jews -- Arizona -- Photographs.; Jews -- California -- Photographs.; Jews -- New Mexico -- Photographs.; Jews -- Texas -- Photographs.; Frontier and pioneer life -- Arizona -- Photographs.; Frontier and pioneer life -- New Mexico -- Photographs.; Frontier and pioneer life -- Texas -- Photographs.; Jewish businesspeople -- Arizona -- Photographs.; Jewish businesspeople -- New Mexico -- Photographs.; Jewish businesspeople -- Texas -- Photographs.; Photographs.; Color photographs.; Black-and-white negatives.; Color negatives.; Slides (Photographs).
Container List
- Series I: Arizona
  - Alpha Phi Omega. (Box 1)
    Group portrait of thirteen women: unidentified; Jeri Feldman; Poje Kalil; unidentified; Betty Liebert Moore; Janet Cohen Krupp; unidentified; unidentified; unidentified; Shirley Alter Franklin. All standing women unidentified (ca. 1940 at the Universi ty of Arizona).
    Group portrait of nineteen seated women. Individuals include Betty Liebert Moore; Jeri Feldman; Poje Kalil; Janet Cohen Krupp and Shirley Alter Franklin. Others in photograph are unidentified (ca. 1938 at the University of Arizona).
  - Amado, Melissa. (Box 1)
    Photographs from David Burkhalter.
    Page of NEGATIVES of Melissa Amado and Ruth Reed Miller (September 3, 1993).
    1991 conference on the Inquisition in the Americas.
    New Years day (1991).
  - Appel, Nathan B.: Two photocopies of photographs of Nathan Benjamin Appel - territorial chief of police in Tucson. One original photograph of Nathan Benjamin Appel (1846). (Box 1)
  - Arizona Experience And Anne Frank Exhibit: Photographs from Alice Amado showing the Arizona Experience Exhibit and the Anne Frank Exhibit. Arizona Experience was a multicultural exhibit that displayed issues of discrimination and intolerance in Arizona (open to the public August 28 - Septembe r 22, 1995). (Box 1)
  - Arizona Jewish merchants: Exhibit of Arizona Jewish Merchants (1994 from Arizona Jewish Historical Society/Greater Phoenix Chapter). (Box 1)
  - Arizona Pioneer Jews show. (Box 1)
    SLIDES.
    NEGATIVES.
  - Arizona Territory: Maps. (Box 1)
  - Alef Tzadek Alef (AZA) in Tucson 1941; unidentified: Photograph of an unidentified social event. Tucson girls have dates with boys from Phoenix AZA - Congregation Al 1941. (Box 1)
  - Barth, Solomon and family. (Box 1)
    Photographs of Solomon Barth and the Barth family (Solomon Barth lived 1842-1928).
    Portrait of Frederika Barth (mother of Solomon Barth).
    Portrait of Clara Barth (sister or daughter of Solomon Barth). Clara was born in 1882.
    Photograph of Barth Mercantile.
    Group portrait of (top row, l-r): Carl Blassingame; Tom Perez; Commodore Owens; Dan Dubois; Dr. Dalby(?). (bottom row, l-r): Solomon Barth; St. George Creaghe; John Doyle Lee.
  - Bellman, Lamar and family. (Box 1)
    Photographs of Lamar Bellman who was a pioneer merchant and owned a small army/navy store called Bellman's Department Store in Safford, Arizona; married to Celia Levy.
    Two photographs of Bellman on a tractor.
    Photograph of Bellman with a car.
    Photograph of two other photographs. One photograph is of Ben Bellman in the 1980 (son of Lamar Bellman; Bellman married Evelyn Barnett). The second photograph is of the brand of Lamar Bellman (ca. 1935-1970).
    Group photograph of Bellman with three unidentified men.
  - Bendalin. (Box 1)
    Photographs of unidentified man (Howard Bendalin?). Photograph is taken in front of a farm field. Howard Bendalin was from Lithuania. He started a farm in Arizona in 1936.
    Photograph of a page from Howard Bendalin's original passport. The words "Zemdirbys" and agriculture indicate an "educated farmer." This was the basis for his admission to the United States in the 1930s.
  - Bilgray, Rabbi Albert: Photograph of Rabbi Albert T. Bilgray and Rabbi Jacob Ott at a conference entitled "The Hidden Jews of the Southwest" (University of Arizona, January 27, 1991). (Box 1)
  - Bloom, David and Leona. (Box 1)
    Billboard sign for Dave Bloom and Sons store (1971).
    Advertisement on the side of bus (1971).
    Board of Directors of the Men's Club of Temple Emanu-El on December 1, 1947 in Tucson, Arizona. Sitting around the table form left to right were: Louis Shenkarow; M. Bernfeld; L. Sakin; Saul Deittel; David Bloom; Rabbi Albert Bilgray; D. Hirsh; B. Va n; William LeBoff Pragg (?).
    Advertisement on the side of a bus (December 1973).
    Dave Bloom in a suit and hat.
    Herb Bloom in a suit and hat holding a camera.
    David Arthur Bloom, Joe Haggar, and an unidentified man.
    Display case at the front of the store which reads "Lakeland Profile of Fashion!"
    Playboy Bunny standing in front of suits - probably at the Dave Bloom and Sons Store (March 1968).
    Unidentified group of men standing around a Playboy Bunny. In the front of the photograph were (l-r): Herb Bloom; the Playboy Bunny; Ted Bloom; and Dave Bloom.
    Herb Bloom shaking an unidentified man's hand under "Lakeland" sign (1973).
    Horse drawn carriage with advertisement for "Dave Bloom and Sons" on its side in the Tucson Rodeo Parade. In the carriage: Herb Bloom; Dave Bloom; Ted Bloom (1971).
    Unidentified man and woman by a "Lakeland for Sport" sign (December 1970).
    Two unidentified men shaking hands in front of a "Lakeland" sign.
    Display case in the store which holds a sneak preview of the fall sweater fashions.
    Display case in the Dave Bloom and Sons store entitled "Canyon Colors."
    Photographs of an unidentified boy on a swing; at the beach; jumping into a bush; jumping into a pile of seaweed; sitting in the sand putting on a cowboy boot.
    Photographs from J. Robert Burns of two unidentified men wearing football uniforms jumping in the air; two unidentified men wearing football uniforms.
  - Bloom family. (Box 1)
    N.A.R.C.F. Convention - Dorothy and Louis Rothschild; Imelda and Henry Loeb; Herb Fixler and Dave and Lee Bloom (February, 1960). Black and white.
    Bloom family - Dave Sr. and Clara Bloom; their three sons and wives; another couple.
    Photograph of first high school banquet (1940).
    Color photograph of Herb Bloom, Danny Thomas and Dave Bloom, Jr.
    Photograph of H. Koffler, Lee Bloom, Dave Bloom, Jr., and Abe Chanin (October 14, 1986).
    Man and Woman of the Year (Paul Plunkett and Ella Brazelle). Dave Bloom, Jr. is also in the photo (December 15, 1965).
    Initiation of Alpha Delta Sigma (Dave Bloom, Jr. - seated, third from left; January, 1953).
    City of Hope Awards (1988). Left to right: Betty Rosen (Ex. City of Hope); Herbert Ferrin Bloom; Ted Ferrin Bloom; David Arthur Bloom, Jr.; Fred Rosen (National Board of Directors, City of Hope).
    Three women seated outdoors at a picnic table.
    Confirmation class at Temple Emanu-El. Alan Bloom - son of Dave and Lee Bloom - is third from left in second row (1958).
    Nikki Bloom in his soccer uniform (son of Alan and Nan; 1994).
    Photograph of Alan Bloom, Jeffry Bloom and Harold Aarons as children.
    Framed school photo of Richard Bloom (son of Dave and Leona Bloom).
    School photographs of Richard Bloom (son of Dave and Leona; 1958-1959).
    "Happy Holidays" photo card featuring Zachary Bloom (son of Alan and Nan Bloom; 1994). Writing to grandparents (Dave and Leona Bloom) on back.
    Matted baby photo of Barb Reinhardt (name not legible).
    El Zaribah (Tucson Patrol) group photograph with names on back.
  - Bloom family business. (Box 1)
    Photograph of Myers & Bloom Store. Dave Bloom, Sr. (rear, far right; 1911).
    Myers & Bloom Store Dave Bloom, Sr. (left) and J. Cress Myers (1906).
    A horse-drawn carriage featuring an advertisement for Dave Bloom and Sons. Carriage is in front of store; appears to be in a parade.
    At fire prevention program. Dave Bloom, Jr. (standing left; June 1, 1954).
  - Bloom Southwest Jewish Archives inauguration. (Box 1)
    Bloom Southwest Jewish Archives inauguration (October 23, 1988) Photograph shows Elizabeth Ramenofsky, author of From Charcoal To Banking, at the autographing table.
    Mrs. Bertha Breger and Mrs. Sylvia Plotkin.
    The book sale.
    A photo display.
    University of Arizona President H. Koffler.
    Abe S. Chanin introducing the speakers.
    President H. Koffler & director Chanin.
    Harry Rosensweig; Sandy Bloom; Ted Bloom; Dave Bloom.
    Ralph Feffer; Director Abe Chanin.
    Mr. & Mrs. David A. Bloom being honored.
    An unidentified couple.
    3 contact sheets.
    Floyd Fierman signing his book, Roots & Boots.
    Floyd Fierman addressing a group.
    Floyd Fierman with Bertha Breger and an unidentified woman.
    Bertha Breger and an unidentified woman looking at the book Pioneer Jews.
  - Bloom Southwest Jewish Archives open house. (Box 1)
    (April 23, 1995) The Bloom Archives' World Wide Web exhibits being viewed by Melissa Amado and Ray Thompson.
    Harry and Paula Karchmer - signers in the Endowment Book of Life.
    Stuart Glogoff and Gene Amado.
    Jennifer Wolinsky.
    Buffet table.
    Sophia Truneh and her son Jared.
    Herman "Cappy" Capsuto and his wife Libby Capsuto.
    Leonard Dinnerstein (Director of Judaic Studies) and Carol Karsch (Executive Director of the Jewish Community Foundation of Southern Arizona).
    Harry Karchmer, Paula Karchmer, and Stuart Glogoff viewing Web exhibit.
    Herman Capsuto, Jennifer Wolinsky, and James Abel viewing exhibit.
    Herman Capsuto and Jennifer Wolinsky viewing Web exhibit.
    Herman Capsuto, Jennifer Wolinsky, and Sophia Truneh at Web exhibit.
    Capsutos, Jennifer Wolinsky, and James Abel viewing Web exhibit.
    Stuart Glogoff, Carol Karsch, Esther Sherberg, James Abel, and Melissa Amado.
    Harry Karchmer, Glogoffs, viewing Web exhibit.
    Oscar Denenbergs, and L. Glogoff viewing Web exhibit.
    Shaol Pozes, M. Amado, S. Glogoff, and Evie Pozez viewing Web exhibit
    Dean Carla Stoffle, S. Glogoff, and Evie Pozez viewing Web exhibit
    S. Glogoff and Evie Pozez viewing Web exhibit.
    S. Glogoff, E. Pozez, and M. Amado viewing the Web exhibit.
    NEGATIVES (April 23, 1995).
  - Bloom Southwest Jewish Archives, Sinclair Library dedication. (Box 1)
    Dedication (Mar. 25, 1990) - Dave Bloom; Leona Bloom; President Henry Koffler.
    Abe Chanin; Dave Bloom; two unidentified men.
    Contact sheets.
  - Bloom, Ted: Portrait of Ted Bloom by Ray Manley Portraits (1993). (Box 1)
  - Brandes, Ray and Elsie: Ray and Elsie Brandes. (Box 1)
  - Breger, Rabbi Marcus. (Box 2)
    Marcus Breger at unidentified synagogue.
    Breger (by Smith Studios, ca. 1945) - served overseas as military chaplain.
    Breger (by Gene Lindsey).
    Group portrait during Passover on Okinawa.
    Group photograph: Breger; Maurice Folkow; an unidentified man wearing tallis, holding prayer books, and standing in front of a sculpture of the Ten Commandments.
    Group portrait; gathered around a table.
    Breger standing in front of a table; tablecloth bears the words "Holy, Holy."
    Breger and his wife; unidentified woman.
    Breger looking through a telescope.
    Bregers in the "wilderness".
    World War II memorabilia from Japan.
    Bertha Breger - wife of Marcus; unidentified child in front of a car.
  - Brown M. J. (Box 2)
    M.J. Brown; instrumental in starting B'nai B'rith and its junior organization in Tucson and Arizona; helped start the Tucson Lodge (now M.J. Brown Lodge) and Temple Emanu-El in the 1910s.
    Brown on a horse (Tucson 1947).
  - Cabat, Erni and Rose. (Box 2)
    Portrait of Erni and Rose (February 26, 1987; Cabat Studio - 627 N. 4th Ave., Tucson).
    Viewing art of the Cabats: Anna Glass (mother of Mrs. Dottie Erman); Seneca Erman; Rabbi Jordan Cohen; Cantor Janece Erman Cohen; Rose Cabat; Esther Mangel; Inez and Bernie Sloane; Mrs. Dottie Erman.
    Cabat family: Rose; George; Erni; Michael; June (1949; Driscoll St., Tucson).
  - Capin family. (Box 2)
    Samuel Capin (ca. 1925).
    Samuel Capin (1877-1931) - merchant in Tucson; President of Congregation Anshei Israel.
    Dora Loon Capin (1875-1939) - married Hyman Capin.
    Dora Loon Capin - grandson Harlan Capin (1930-); 1932.
    Lillian Bracker Capin (ca.1925).
    Capin children: Sadye; Philip; Bessie; Samuel Capin.
    Rebecca Goldstein Bracker (1866-1951) - married Herman Bracker; daughter married Samuel Capin.
    Bracker family: Joseph; Molly; Ada; Rose; Fanny; Lilian; Lillian Bracker married Samuel Capin.
    Portrait of Hyman Capin family: Sam; Ben; Zellie; Jake; Hilliard; Robert Marcus; Sadye Capin Marcus; Philip; Fanny; Blossom Chernon; Harry; Bessie Capin Chernin; Ione Marcus; Sam Marcus; Hyman Capin; Blossom Capin; Dora Loon Capin; Ruth Chernin; Gert rude Chernin (ca.1924 1926).
    Group photograph: Phil Capin; Dan Smith; Mayor Lois Hudgin; unidentified others - in Nogales (ca. 1940s) in front of aluminum deposit.
    Group photo: Jake and Zellie Capin (April 15, 1970); the day of groundbreaking for their 101-room Americana Motor Hotel in Nogales.
    Group photo: Zellie Capin; unidentified others at Bohemia Club, Sonora, Mexico.
  - Cemetery headstones (Tucson). (Box 2)
    Louis N. Cohen - son of Nathan and Rebecca Cohen (died August 5, 1887).
    I.F.Coppel (died Feb. 3, 1804).
    Joseph and Therese Ferrin (died Oct.16, 1926 and Feb. 25, 1911, respectively).
    Harry Greenblatt (died 1915).
    Morris Grossman (died April 24, 1918).
    Fischel Klein (died June 19, 1915).
    William Lans (died 1907).
    Morris Metzner (died Feb. 18, 1904).
    Eugenie Meyer (died July 6, 1916).
    Ben Spodeck.
    Gus Klein Stiffel (died Sept. 2, 1907).
    Amelie Stiffel (died June 10, 1925).
    Mitchell Gilbert Zuroff (died Oct. 14, 1927).
    Two contact prints showing memorial headstones of the persons listed above.
    Other headstones.
  - Chanin, Abraham and Mildred. (Box 2)
    At archives seminar - Sheraton of Prescott, Arizona (1991). NEGATIVES.
    Speaking at a B'nai B'rith meeting (Tucson Jewish Community Center; 1993).
    Mildred Chanin at conference on the Inquisition and Hidden Jews (Tucson; Jan. 27, 1991).
    SLIDE of A.Chanin at the Bloom Southwest Jewish Archives.
  - Clifton (AZ) mining and railroads. (Box 2)
  - Cohen, David: David Cohen (ca. 1932-1933; Tucson). (Box 2)
  - Cohen, M.D. and Harriet: Portrait: in front of an unidentified house. (Box 2)
  - Combined Jewish Appeal. (Box 2)
    Combined Jewish Appeal meeting in Tucson.
    Women's Jewish Appeal leadership meeting (1956).
    Combined Jewish appeal leadership meeting (1960s); Jud Kane and Donald Diamond.
    Eleanor Roosevelt; Mrs. Mark Lefkovitz; Mrs. Meyer Cohen; Mrs. I. Horowitz; Mrs. Morris Shanhouse (January 26, 1961; Jewish Community Center).
  - Congregation Beis Menachem (Phoenix): Mikveh under construction at Congregation Beis Menachem (formerly Tiphereth Israel) - Chabad of Greater Phoenix. (Box 2)
  - Davis, Lewis. (Box 2)
    Mr. and Mrs. Davis and unidentified others around a table.
    Lew Davis and unidentified man.
    Davis; Mr. and Mrs. Christopher; Mr. Mardian; at Passover Seder (1961?).
    Davis and unidentified others at Passover Seder (November 1961?).
    Lew Davis; M. Khazyan; others; at Passover Seder (1961?).
  - Diamond brothers. (Box 2)
    Benjamin Diamond next to his delivery horse and wagon (1917).
    Luis Diamond behind the bar; other men at Bassett Tower (Tucson).
    Diamond Brothers Cleaners; standing by the desk is Benjamin Diamond; seated at the desk is his brother, Luis Diamond (1917).
  - Dickstein/Bromi: One contact sheet of photographs of two men in a car (Box 2)
  - Dietrich family. (Box 2)
    Harvey Dietrich and unidentified others with prize steer(1951)
    Sign: "Sun Land Beef Co."
    Harvey Dietrich standing in front of several teepees.
    Harvey Dietrich riding a horse.
    Harvey Dietrich using a branding iron.
    One contact print showing various Dietrich family photographs.
  - Douglas cemetery restoration. (Box 2)
    Restoration occurred Nov. 22-Dec. 6, 1992; rededication on April 25, 1993.
    Headstone for Nathan Cohen (1852-1936) - one of the few intact gravesites.
    Headstone for Ben Greenberg (1893-1942).
    Headstone for Ilitzky.
    Headstone for Ben Silver (died April 2, 1926).
    Road near the Douglas cemetery.
    Abe Chanin speaking to a group of unidentified people.
    Mitch Dorson leading a prayer.
    Mitch Dorson looking at a headstone.
    Memorial.
    Unidentified group of people standing among several headstones.
    Cochise County and University of Arizona Hillel volunteers restoring cemetery.
    Jesus Montano and Michael Boldt during their lunch break.
    Unidentified woman working on the restoration.
    Michelle Mordka Rubin.
    Alon Becker.
    Two contact sheets of the restoration.
  - Douglas Military Camp: Harry Baelion (?) and a horse at a military camp in Douglas, Arizona (June 1918). (Box 2)
  - Drachman, Harry. (Box 2)
    Group photo: three women; two men standing by stone wall (Drachman is second from the right).
    Two unidentified women standing in front of a house.
    Unidentified woman in front of a car in the woods.
    Group photo: in front of a car and trees (1938).
    Unidentified group posing on a wall.
    Group photo: Henry Levine; Jaoquin A. Legarra; Harry Glucksman; Drachman.
  - Drachman, Philip: Mr. and Mrs. Drachman (post 1868; New York City). (Box 2)
  - Drachman, Samuel. (Box 2)
    Samuel Drachman.
    Document: contract between Drachman and Albert Steinfeld(1883).
    Jenny Migel Drachman.
    At Palace Cigar Store (132 W. Congress St., Tucson Arizona): Sam Katzenstein (miner); Samuel H. Drachman; Owen T. Rousse (attorney).
  - Feldman, Alther Marcus Sr. (Box 2)
    Home in Tucson, Arizona.
    Contact sheet: A.M. Feldman and his home.
  - Ferrin home: Former Ferrin home (Tucson, Arizona; 1990). (Box 2)
  - Fireman, Bert: Portrait. (Box 2)
  - Franklin family. (Box 2)
    Victoria Jacobs Franklin (1860).
    Maurice A. Franklin (1862).
    Louis Abraham Franklin.
    Selim Franklin.
    Selim Franklin; Maurice Franklin; Louis Abraham Franklin.
  - Franklin home: Franklin home (406 N. Main St., Tucson,Arizona; 1990). (Box 2)
  - Fruchthendler, Jacob. (Box 2)
    Group photo: Fruchthendler being honored.
    Fruchthendler congratulating Lawrence Irell of Los Angeles.
    Group photo: Fruchthendler; Martin Ginsburg; S.L. Schorr; unidentified person (1967).
    Group photo: Martin Volk; Arthur Goldberg; Fred Rosen; Donald Diamond; Fruchthendler.
    Fruchthendler School (Cloud Road, Tucson).
    Group photo: in front of "Royal Hawaiian."
  - Giss, Maurice: Bar Mitzvah - with his parents Harold and Goldie Giss of Yuma. (Box 2)
  - Gold, Charles. (Box 2)
    Mr. and Mrs. Charles Gold and child of Tucson.
  - Goldbaum, Julius. (Box 2)
    Exterior of house (1990; Tucson).
    Exterior of house; "Old Town Artisans" sign (1990).
    "Wine Barrel " ceiling in Courtyard Cafe (1990).
  - Goldbaum, Nathan and Emma: Nathan and Emma Goldbaum (ca.1935). (Box 2)
  - Goldberg family: Group photo: Aaron Goldberght. (Box 2)
  - Goldwater family. (Box 2)
    Michael Goldwater residence (1890s; Prescott).
    Morris Goldwater - from the Arizona Historical Foundation.
    Morris Goldwater (1879) - served as Mayor of Prescott.
    Goldwater store in Prescott, AZ.
    Interior of the Goldwater Store.
    Henry Goldwater at home (Prescott).
    NEGATIVES; Goldwater family photo.
    Sam Goldwater (1880; photographer: Erwin Baer).
    Joseph Goldwater.
    Sen. Barry Goldwater in Tucson, Arizona.
    Michael Goldwater.
    Henry Goldwater's home (Prescott; ca. 1890s).
    Goldwater's store (1880s) with views of city and countryside.
    M. Goldwater & Bro. Store (ca.1880; Erwin Baer photographer).
  - Gotthelf, Isadore: Interior of American Grocery (ca.1880). (Box 2)
  - Grossman house: Benjamin N. Brook; Grossmans; William Gordon. (Box 2)
  - Grossman, Lou: Street scene from Oatman, Arizona; Grossman standing in the crowd holding a megaphone. (Box 2)
  - Grouskay, Eli. (Box 2)
    Grouskay with grandchildren: Renee; Randy; Karen.
    Sign which states "Legacy of the Land Arizona's Jewish Ranchers and Farmers."
    Cartoon of Eli Grouskay's penchant for feeding his cattle until they became enormous.
    Four unidentified men at the Arizona National Livestock show(1960).
    Unidentified man; sign which reads "Grouskay Cattle Co." and "Grouskay Feeding Co."
    Unidentified man riding a horse.
    Unidentified man in a corral with several cows.
    Contact sheet.
  - Handmaker, I.H. (Box 2)
  - Har Zion Congregation (Paradise Valley): Views of the front door, sanctuary, ark, lecterns, tree of life, and memorial plaques. (Box 2)
  - International Conference On Inquisition/Hidden Jews(Tucson, Jan. 27, 1991). (Box 2)
    Stan Hordes; Harriet Rochlin; Francis Hernandez; Tomas Atencio.
    Mildred Chanin; Beth Chanin Rudolph; Stan Hordes; Dr.Salvador Martinez; Eduardo Garrigues.
    Two contact sheets of the conference.
    Daniel Swetchinski; Gunter Bohm; Ruth Reed; Stan Hordes;Mildred Chanin.
  - Jacobs family. (Box 2)
    Lionel M. Jacobs.
    Barron M. Jacobs.
    Henrietta Jacobs.
    Store front sign which reads "Jacobs Block."
  - Jewish Family Services. (Box 3)
    Group photo: doctors panel; chairperson, Dr. Boris Zemsky(1951).
    Group photo: Jack Cole; Lilian Rosensweig; Sanders Solot;Bunny Epstein; Dave Garber. Seated (l-r): Lillian Goldwyn; Betty Brook; Jean Myerson (1977).
  - Joint Distribution Committee: Ben Brook; Herbert Lehman(ca. 1943). (Box 3)
  - Katzenstein, Sam: NEGATIVES of a document entitled "Index to Real Estate Grants - Pima County, AZ." (Box 3)
  - Kellner, E.B.: Newman; E.B.Kellner(1880s) (Box 3)
  - Klein, Matilde. (Box 3)
    Sukkah; Klein's Boarding House (700 block E. 3rd St., Tucson;ca. 1940).
    Matilde Klein (ca. 1941).
    Unidentified group (1942).
  - Koffler, Henry. (Box 3)
  - Krupp, Alvin and Janet Cohen: Portrait. (Box 3)
  - Lantin, Max: Lantin's Store (Globe, AZ;1880s). (Box 3)
  - Lesinsky. (Box 3)